Inventory of the George Caputineanu Minden papers
Hoover Institution Archives
George Caputineanu Minden papers
1943-2006
2007C55
Minden, George Caputineanu, 1921-2006.
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, lists, letters, and financial records, relating to United States government-sponsored book distribution in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research. Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives Audiovisual Specialist for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2007
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Chief, Romanian desk, Free Europe Press; president, International Literary Center.
Scope and Content of Collection
Reports, lists, letters, and financial records, relating to United States government-sponsored book distribution in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Free Europe Press.; International Literary Center.; Books and reading--Soviet Union.; Books and reading--Europe, Eastern.
Container List
- Biographical file (Box 1)
  - General (Box 1)
  - Notebooks (Box 1)
- Book distribution project (Box 1)
- Correspondence (Box 1)
- Distribution report (Box 1)
  - 1967 (Box 1)
  - 1969 (Box 1)
  - 1970 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1971 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1972 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1973 (Box 1)
- European trip report (Box 2)
  - 1973 (Box 2)
  - 1974 (Box 2)
  - 1976 (Box 2)
  - 1977 (Box 2)
    (notes only)
  - 1978 (Box 2)
  - 1979 (Box 2)
    - June (Box 2)
    - October-November (Box 2)
  - 1980 (Box 2)
  - 1981 (Box 2)
  - 1982 (Box 2)
  - 1983 (Box 2)
    - May-June (Box 2)
    - October-November (Box 2)
  - 1984 (Box 2)
    - May-June (Box 2)
    - November (Box 2)
  - 1985 (Box 2)
    - May (Box 2)
    - December (Box 2)
  - 1987 (Box 3)
  - 1988 (Box 3)
    - June (Box 3)
    - October-November (Box 3)
  - 1989 (Box 3)
  - 1990 (Box 3)
    - June (Box 3)
    - November-December (Box 3)
- Distribution statistics, 1982 (Box 3)
- International Advisory Council, 1970 (Box 3)
- Presentation, 1969 (Box 3)
- Project's purposes, 1966 (Box 3)
- Publications and Special Projects Division (Box 3)
  - Annual report (Box 3)
    - 1966 (Box 3)
    - 1967 (Box 3)
    - 1969 (Box 3)
  - Budget, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
- Receipts from Biblioteka Narodowa, 1983 (Box 3)
- Sponsors (Box 3)
  - Domestic (Box 3)
  - Europe (Box 3)
- United States Intelligence Activities. Executive Order, 1981 (Box 3)